#### Paul Wallas. Résumé.

#### Introduction

I'm an experienced, multi-disciplined designer with a passion for creating seamless and delightful user experiences. I have skills covering a wide range of disciplines, including UX/UI, Web, Interaction and Print design. I'm currently Head of Design at RightIndem.

#### Skills

**User Focused** via the creation of user personas, scenarios and user journeys that map to release schedules. Encourage role play to help all team members put their minds in those of the user.

**Visual** design skills focusing on web, web application, print, iconography and the creation and maintenance of brand assets and product style guides. Experienced using Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign.

**Interaction** skills focusing on the creation of UI wireframes both low and hi-fidelity mock-ups using Sketch, Invision Adobe XD and Balsamig.

**Front-end development** with knowledge of HTML, CSS, SCSS and React. Some knowledge of JS, GIT and GULP. Experienced working in an agile environment.

**Management** skills with experience of candidate selection, conducting interviews, employee appraisals creating employee personal development plans and leading motivated teams.

**Communication** skills with experience in communicating to CEOs, COOs, BAs and PMs, developing user journeys and process flows aligning technical stories to designs within VSTS.

## Education

# Designing for the Web

University of Teesside 2006

# **Industrial Design BA Hons**

University of Teesside 2003 - 2006

**Employment** 

## **Head of Design**

RightIndem August 2016 - Present

# **Design Team Lead**

FACE Recording & Measurement Systems October 2009 - Present

# Web Designer

Soula Design September 2006 - October 2009

### Current Role

Managing and coaching a team of enthusiastic, multi-disciplined designers, I'm responsible for the visual and user experience of the RightIndem product suite.

During my time at RightIndem, I have implemented a series of changes to the design process, improving team efficiency, discoverability and clarity. These changes include the introduction of GIT design file management, Zeplin to serve as a communication tool between the design and development teams and Invision as a communication channel between external clients and internal BAs.

I have delivered 'lunch & learn' sessions to help individuals outside of the design team understand visual design language and I perform a leading role in communicating the importance of user experience to the wider company.

I have conducted user role play sessions, helping team members experience the product through the eyes of our users and I've also ran user sessions outside of our team, reporting user findings to our management and development team.

#### Personal

I have a natural love for user interaction and user psychology, how we make decisions and our emotive drivers. I have a love of typography, understanding basic typographic elements and overall visual composition.

Outside of work my passion is football, keeping fit (unless it's December) and food. I'm quite a big 'foodie', enjoying shows like Master Chef and the Great British Bake-Off. I also enjoy the odd Friday beer ale after work.

## Contact

Web paulwallas.com Twitter /paulwallas Email paulwallas@me.com Phone 0771 383 2372